[horn honks]
[Jerry] This is a 1964 Morgan Plus 4,
in brilliant blue with a black interior.
It has a four-speed manual gear box...
[engine revs]
...and dual carbs
feeding a 105-horsepower motor.
Morgans are unbelievable cars.
They're very British.
Brits like tradition.
This basic design has been
in production since 1936.
The frame is actually made of ash wood,
which makes no sense.
Wood is not for cars.
It's for ventriloquist dummy heads.
These cars are so cool to me
because they just don't care
what the other companies are doing.
A lot like my very special guest today,
Mr. Stephen Colbert...
former host of The Colbert Report,
and has recently been picked by CBS
to replace David Letterman
and be their late-night talk show star.
You never told me it was fun!
[Jerry] Stephen also looks like
a very conventional, functional person
but inside his head, he's a madman.
-Oh, my God.
-Can you dig it?
[phone ringing]
-[Stephen] Hello?
-[Jerry] Stephen?
-[Stephen] Jerry?
-[Jerry] Are your children at home?
[Stephen] No, they're not.
That's an odd lead to a conversation,
I have to say, though.
[Jerry laughs]
[Jerry] I wanted to have breakfast
with somebody amusing, someone witty.
[Stephen] I'm out of practice.
I haven't had a television show
for almost five months.
[Jerry] Come and see yourself
as a sports car.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians In Cars Getting Coffee.
-[dog barking]
-Hey.
Scratch, now lick. There it is.
[Stephen] Wow...
-Is this original?
-[Jerry] Yeah.
It's wood frame,
so you don't have to worry about rust,
but you do have to worry about termites.
[Stephen] It's gorgeous.
I want to ask you for a stick of Beemans
before I strap in here.
-I think my beard even matches this.
-[Jerry laughs]
-Whose car is that, the wife?
-[Stephen] That is my daughter's.
-Your daughter?
-Soon to be my son's.
-Sex change?
-That's...
We don't know.
Is it just a matter of time
before transgender is an airline?
You just get on one sex
and you get off, you're the other one.
[Stephen]
It really has that airplane feel to it.
I feel like we're about to fly across
the English Channel
to save the people stranded in Dover.
Perhaps someday we could rent
a cottage on the Isle of Wight.
-If it's not too dear. Yeah.
-If it's not too dear. Exactly.
[Jerry] Turn signals,
you're gonna love this.
[clicking]
Here's my horn.
[horn honking]
Would not help you in any way.
"We're British, we don't need help.
-We're just fine as we are."
-Everything...
Take out the little book, too,
I love the book.
Does it have, like,
a section on etiquette in here?
"Do not interrupt the driver mid-shift."
-How adorable. It's adorable.
-Fantastic.
A little mouse should live in there.
[giggling]
A little mouse,
his name is Wilfred, he goes...
"Can I get master anything?"
-[Stephen] Is this a '64?
-[Jerry] '64.
-I was born in '64.
-No.
Yeah. I love how dangerous this feels.
Watch this.
[Stephen laughing]
-Is that the most precious...
-And open up this,
and Wilfred is on a little bike.
[both laughing]
On a chain, making them move.
"I wasn't aware that it was spinning,
master!"
I started off thinking
I was gonna be an actor,
and then got hired by Second City,
and did sketch comedy,
and cabaret for years.
I started The Daily Show on June 2, 1997.
But that was Craig Kilborn years.
And then I left.
Though I came back in 2000
for the election,
and there was this new guy hosting,
Jon Stewart, who my wife knew, actually.
She always lords it over me that
she's known Jon longer than I have.
I think his roommate dated her roommate,
or something like that.
-Right.
-When he got the gig,
she was like, "That's Jon Leibowitz,
what's he doing? He's not funny."
You're one of the greatest
television performers I have ever seen.
-Can I get out here?
-I'm just telling you that.
-That's very nice of you to say.
-You really are. On TV.
You had to do that.
You had to put "on TV."
Well, I've never seen...
You're not a stage performer.
-I was at a certain point.
-But I never saw any of that.
-Telling you what I saw.
-No one will.
There's a lot of people on TV, Stephen.
-A lot.
-You're very nice.
[Jerry] What you did with that character,
and the energy and the fun,
-you never seemed tired.
-I was ready to stop.
-You were?
-I was gonna stop
-whether or not...
-Really?
Yeah, the Letterman thing fell in my lap.
Why'd you stop your show?
Your show was a very good show, Jerry.
You're one of the greatest performers
I've ever seen on television. On NBC.
One of the greatest performers
I've ever seen on NBC.
[door handle clicking]
-Let me reach over there...
-Not only a death trap...
-A suicide trap.
-Yep.
We better get out while we're young.
[inaudible conversation]
What time would you get home at night?
For the first couple of years,
it was like I lived there.
I tried to be, like, the first guy in,
and then I wouldn't leave
till 11:00 at night.
Wow.
Yeah, 'cause we didn't know
what we were doing.
Can we start with some coffee?
-Sure.
-Thank you.
I saw your beard recently, and I thought,
"If he hasn't shaved,
this is gonna be gruesome."
But I see that you're...
I'm going for a mid-career Connery.
-A "mid-Connery," we call it.
-A mid-Connery.
When I was in Chicago
and I'd be auditioning,
-never got anything, by the way.
-Really?
I think I got one Iowa Bank commercial.
So remember these three words
for banking convenience.
"You're first here..."
...at FirsTier.
[Jerry laughs]
I like the way you adjust your glasses.
What did I do?
Yes. It's refined.
It's like cleaning your pipe.
If you had a pipe,
you could do this, you go, "Well, Jerry...
Jerry, let me..."
Come on, let's be honest,
a pipe and a beard is gross.
-It's just gross.
-What, 'cause it lingers?
Just, everything is hanging and yellow,
the cheese, the eggs, it's all yellow.
He's growing beards, he's packing bowls.
The cheese. I don't think
I'm gonna have a good day today.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Have you ever smoked a pipe?
Uh, no, but I own several nice pipes.
I can't believe you could
do that pipe thing
without being a pipe smoker.
You did that so well.
I'm sure you have talents.
This is my biggest one.
-Noticing? Noticing?
-Noticing what the hell's going on.
That's very nice. My dad smoked a pipe.
My dad smoked a pipe...
-That's where you got it from.
-He ran a hospital.
-Ever see Hospital with George C. Scott?
-Of course.
I would like to talk
about George C. Scott.
George C. Scott.
-Are we ever...
-The Flim-Flam Man.
-...gonna see...
-Patton.
...those guys again?
I did a show at Second City once, where
we were doing a "men's movement" scene,
where we're all getting in touch
with our primal masculinity.
Five guys are in the scene,
we all started chanting,
"George C. Scott. George C. Scott."
That was the most masculine thing
we could say.
Steve McQueen has become a symbol
of what men used to be that we miss.
It would be wonderful to find out
that Steve McQueen was gay, though.
Him and Charles Bronson.
Yeah, you... Come on.
-Come on. Are you kidding?
-Come on, wake up.
Morning, noon, and night.
He was running around with Rip Taylor,
Paul Lynde, Gomer Pyle.
They had a poker game every Tuesday night.
-Yep.
-Yeah, they're all gay. Everyone's gay.
Not to belabor, though there's nothing
I love more than to belabor.
You saw guys like George C. Scott and go,
"I want to be like that."
Right. Well, also,
it goes with the astronaut core, too.
Laying it out over the line.
That's why I said
when I got in your car,
"You got a stick of Beemans?"
Chuck Yeager, the Beemans,
The Right Stuff.
At the end of that movie,
the last line of it is,
they're driving up on his wreck,
when he's chasing that demon,
and they're looking at the smoke,
and here comes Sam Shepard,
cut up and bloody, but looking good,
and the ambulance driver goes,
"Is that a man?"
And he goes, "Yes, it is."
In other words,
risk-taking and adventurous and...
But what do you think
the missing factor is?
It's "the hell with it."
What got you into this business.
"The hell with it."
-I have no other skills.
-If you think about a...
You could've acquired them.
You acquired this.
What I'm saying to you is,
women are becoming more masculine,
men are becoming more feminine.
Who's more feminine, you or your father?
Obviously I am.
Because he actually smoked,
and I pretend to smoke
with a spoon.
How do you feel about happiness?
Where do you rank happiness?
I think it's a foolish thing to pursue.
Suffering is actually
a pretty good way to get to happiness.
Exactly. Like I'm suffering right now,
trying to make you happy.
You have. You've made me happy, Jerry.
One of the first gigs I got
when I was out of college
was, I did a children's theater show.
The woman who ran the program
was going through a divorce.
She said, "What should I do?"
She laid out the different options
she had, how to handle her relationship.
And I said, "You should think of the thing
that you least want to do.
That's probably the right thing to do.
And you know it.
Which is why you don't want to do it."
And she just looked at me, she goes,
"Are you sure you're not Jewish?"
And I took it as a compliment.
I'm like, "Yeah, that's nice."
-You're obviously...
-Existing is a complete...
What a trial.
One of my favorite Richard Pryor lines,
his bit about racism, he says,
"You know, forget about racism.
It's hard enough just being a person."
Do you know the band Neutral Milk Hotel?
Is that an antacid?
He's got a song, and one of the lines is,
"And someday, we will die
And our ashes will fly
From the airplane over the sea
And when we meet on a cloud
I'll be laughing out loud
I'll be laughing with everyone I see
Can't believe how strange it is
to be anything at all"
And I really love that idea
of how strange it is to be...
Okay, Jerry.
Too much.
What's the last thing you want to taste
right before you die?
Arctic frost blueberry Twizzlers.
Maybe coffee.
You really want to perk up
right at that moment?
It picks you up while it calms you down.
And what's the last thing
you want to hear?
Mendelssohn's Song Without Words,
which is short,
two-and-a-half minutes long or something.
Good, 'cause we don't have a lot of time.
Do you use jazz language at all?
Like "cat," "daddy-o," "dig it"?
I won't say "dig it" or "daddy-o."
-"Can you dig it?"
-"Can you dig it"?
You'll say, "Can you dig it"?
I can say "Dig it."
Really? You got a lot of balls.
Did you like Whiplash?
-Uh, you know what?
-Oh, no.
No, don't.
-What do you think I'm gonna say?
-I know what you're gonna say.
You had some problems with it
and I don't wanna hear it.
I know people who play jazz.
They said, "The idea that
that's how you get good at jazz
is not how you get good at jazz."
-I know.
-And I said,
"I've got a feeling that's not
how you get good at boxing,
but I like Rocky."
What do you think
of the idea for this show?
Jerry.
[Jerry laughs]
How long do we get to do this?
-Whatever you like. We can leave...
-No, no, this is very enjoyable.
-I think the lulls are nice.
-I love the lulls.
I can't talk as long as you can.
You can talk in paragraphs
and just keep going.
Let's do a lull now,
because I'm exhausted.
-One of the--
-That was enough of a lull for you?
Did it get uncomfortable?
Do you have to fill the silences?
This is much longer
than you'll be on my show.
To do a guest appearance on your show,
it's no [bleep] fun.
-This is relaxing.
-Everything...
-This is very relaxing.
-Exactly.
When I come on your show,
I'm gonna do a stand-up set.
Know how long it's gonna take
to put that together?
So, you cannot compare the pain in the ass
of doing your show
to the joy and pleasure of doing mine.
[inaudible]
[Jerry] Which would you rather be,
smart or funny?
-I'd rather be funny.
-Me, too.
So, you'd be a clown, then?
Just an idiot in gigantic pants.
[Jerry] Wanna go in this bookstore?
You think you're so smart.
[Stephen] When I was younger,
living in Chicago,
the one thing I would never deny myself
was books.
That's really pretentious.
Could I drive?
-You can drive a stick?
-Sure.
-How great do you feel with those gloves?
-They feel really nice.
[Jerry] The weird thing, of course,
is that New York is now
the center of talk shows.
-Isn't that interesting?
-That's the weird thing.
But both you and Jimmy Fallon
are adult enough
to not get into any of that.
I think nothing would be more boring
-than Late Night war.
-Yeah.
We had drinks and talked about it,
actually.
-You and Jimmy Fallon?
-Both drunk.
Yeah. It was shortly after it was
announced that I was gonna get the gig.
I said, "Let's get together
and have some drinks,"
and we laughed and told stories.
That's it. We just laughed like this.
And it was lovely.
My favorite thing of today
was George C. Scott.
-George C. Scott.
-He's not coloring his hair.
He doesn't give a [bleep].
-Why?
-Right?
-You think I'm coloring my hair?
-Obviously.
I'm not.
-That was a pretty good lull, though.
-Yeah.
[Jerry] That was...
Might even be our best lull.
[Stephen] Yeah.
[gear grinding]
Oops! Yeah. Yeah, now you're
going into first.
-You wanna go into third.
-There.
-I haven't driven a stick in forever.
-Really?
Not that you can tell.
Here's why, is that I feel...
-Oh, God.
-Sorry.
-[gears grinding]
-No, no, no. Second... No, you...
Wait, nothing at all?
Oh, God, Stephen, no.
You don't know what you're doing.
[engine racing]
Absolutely horrible driving. Horrible.
I'm not gonna get any action
at the end of this, am I?
No.
My kids aren't home.